

Babatunde Abioye



bmabioye@gmail.com

Personal Information

WEBSITES. PORTFOLIOS, **PROFILES** https://www.linkedin/in/bmabioye

https://github.com/bmabioye

https://bmabioye.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Google IT Support Specialist, technology enthusiast, an experienced IT professional with more than 7 years of work in various IT-inclined settings helping small businesses improve productivity. A proactive, servant leader that maximizes the efforts of others toward common goals-a process and detail-oriented individual seeking to advance IT career as an expat.

SKILLS

Customer Service & Support

Operating Systems (Windows, Linux, MacOS)

Computer networking [LAN, WLAN, VLAN]

Programming languages [HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Python] Virtualization

Remote Connections & Cloud Computing

Troubleshooting & Repair

Systems Administration/Configuration

Implementing/managing directory services | Data management

ERP & POS Systems Configuration | CCTV & Intercom Telephony

IT security | Cryptology/encryption | IT Systems/Infrastructure

NATIONALITY DATE OF BIRTH GENDER

Nigeria

27-07-1986

Male

DESIRED POSITION

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST / HELPDESK

Work Experience

DATES

POSITION

RESPONSIBILITIES

June 2015 - present

Business Management Specialist [Self-Employ]

- Proffer business solutions for small and medium enterprises.
- Efficiently and friendly support customers in their business needs
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help regularly.

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS BUSINESS

Lovelamp Systems & Consulting Firm / Ibadan – Nigeria Information Technology | Web Solution | Training

DATES POSITION RESPONSIBILITIES

August 2018 - March 2021

ICT Solution Consultant. [Contract]

- Seamlessly oversaw, managed and coordinated the ICT department
- Procured, managed, and administered computers & other IT infrastructures
- Network monitoring and configuration including routers, VPNs, RDP, etc
- Implement WebApp and integrate solutions into business operations
- Maintained and repaired computers, other IT equipment and tools to sustained uninterrupted operation.

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS TYPE OF BUSINESS

Country Kitchen Ventures / Ibadan – Nigeria Hospitality | Restaurant | Retail



POSITION

RESPONSIBILITIES

August 2017 - March 2020

System Administrator [Contract]

- Setup local and live web-server for WebApp deployment
- Managed and configured remote connection
- Configured Google virtual machines
- -Setup, deployed digital Ocean droplets

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS TYPE OF BUSINESS

XPL Developers / Ibadan – Nigeria Blockchain | Web Development | ICT

DATES

August 2013 - March 2015 [Full-time]

POSITION

Customer Care Representative / Supervisor

- **RESPONSIBILITIES**
- Actively listened to customers' requests, confirming full understanding before addressing concerns
- Prepare a variety of different written communications, reports and documents to ensure smooth operations
- Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS TYPE OF BUSINESS MTN Nigeria Trade Partner / Oshogbo – Nigeria Mobile Operation | Customer Service | Retail | Telecoms

Education and Training

2021

QUALIFICATION AWARDED PRINCIPAL STUDIES

Google IT Support

IT Security | Operating Systems | Computer Networking System Administration and Infrastructure Services Technical Support Fundamentals

INSTITUTION

Coursera / Google

DATES QUALIFICATION AWARDED PRINCIPAL STUDIES 2013

Customer Care Training

Customer Service | Mobile Devices Troubleshooting Mobile Device Configuration | Help Desk | Retail

INSTITUTION

MTN Service Centre, Ibadan

DATES QUALIFICATION AWARDED PRINCIPAL STUDIES

2011

Bachelor of Technology | Mathematics & Computer Science Computer Architecture, Algorithm, Software Design, AI, DBMS

INSTITUTION

Federal University of Technology, Minna - Nigeria

Skills and Competences **LANGUAGE SPOKEN** OTHER LANGUAGE(S)

English [Fluent]

Yoruba [Native], Arabic[Hesitant], Mandarin[Beginner]

Certifications **SOCIAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES**

Comptia A+ Certification Google IT Support Certificate

Accomplishments

2018

DATE PROJECT USE CASE

Use Microsoft Excel to build a loan management application Community Effort